Previously on
Pretty Little Liars...
I still feel like we're
rushing this.
I'm not the one calling the shots.
Who are you?
– I'm Lyndon James. Nate doesn't exist.
Mona has people watching their every move.
There's no way that she has
someone watching all of us.
We can put an end to this.
He's the father of my son.
Yeah, he deserves to know that.
I need some time to sort this all out.
If he figures out that I'm lying to him...
– He won't.
Everything okay?
It's my powerhouse potion.
Aria knows that you saw Alison that night.
I swear, I didn't hurt Alison.
Last chance to save yourself.
Yes, it is.
Is this what you're looking for?
Will you just tell me that what
I saw tonight wasn't real?
Please tell me.
Spencer needs to talk to her sister.
Okay, but she needs to
talk to one of us first.
I've tried her, like, three
times with no answer.
Yeah. I haven't heard from her either,
and neither has Hanna.
I wonder if we should even tell her at all.
Do you remember when we thought
Melissa was torturing us?
Aria, your dad said that he saw Melissa
outside Ali's house the
night she was murdered.
I don't think she was out
for an evening stroll.
She must know something.
I know, I just... think we should hold off.
I've gotta go. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Come in.
Hey. I thought you were
coming back downstairs.
I have to work super early tomorrow.
What's that?
It's for you.
It came in this morning, but I wasn't sure
if I should give it to you or not.
Why? What is it?
James family...?
I don't know a James family in Chicago.
Wasn't that Nate's real name?
Look, honey, do you want me just to take it
down to the police station?
– No.
Really, 'cause I could just
have one of the police
officers open it for you.
Mom, you just started working there.
They're gonna ask you a
million questions about...
Me, about Maya, about Nate, and...
Why I ever trusted him.
Look, I never should have
brought this up here.
No, don't take it. I want to open it.
Why did he have these?
These are all things I gave to Ali.
Maya must have found them in Ali's house
and tried to give them back to me.
Look, sweetie, just put the
stuff away and come downstairs.
No, no, I'm fine. I...
I just hate the thought of
him touching any of this.
Why would they send this to me?
I guess they're just doing what they can.
You know, they couldn't undo
what their son did, so...
I should have just opened that myself.
Look, are you sure you don't
wanna just come downstairs?
Not tonight. I'm really tired.
I should probably just go to bed.
All right.
Why are you sitting in the dark?
I'm not.
– Your arm still bothering you?
Not so much.
How did you hurt yourself again?
It was stupid. I just slipped in gym.
Well, don't you think it's something
a doctor should take a look at?
Mom, seriously, I'm fine.
I can type with one hand.
Well, clearly, you need two to wash a pot.
Typing is not scraping.
How's school going?
Is it still difficult
to see Mona every day?
We only have two classes together.
Two's a lot.
If it's distracting, I can
talk to Mr Tamborelli
and help you transfer...
Mom, she'd still be there.
I'm not gonna avoid going
down every hallway.
I understand.
I-I'm just trying to protect...
Why do you think I need protection?
I meant... to protect your education.
Is there something else
I need to know about?
Is it happening again?
Hanna?
– No, there's nothing.
I just don't need anyone
else protecting me, okay?
One caped crusader is enough.
Who's wearing the cape? Caleb?
I have to take a shower.
Has Caleb been tangling with Mona?
"Tangling"?
I don't even know what that means.
Has Mona said anything to you recently,
or done something to make...?
– No.
He just doesn't trust her.
He thinks she should be watched.
You know, I-I think I am
gonna call Mr Tamborelli.
Don't. I can deal with Mona and Caleb.
Just... leave it alone.
I'm glad to hear that
you're getting her help.
Like I said, I just hope that
she makes a full recovery,
and I know that my daughter
feels the same way.
Thank you.
You too, Mr Sorenson.
Well, I just got off the phone
with Meredith's father.
Wow. That must have been weird.
Turns out Meredith has a long history of...
Issues.
He thinks that she stopped taking her meds,
and I told him that we didn't
want to see her punished,
we wanted to see her treated.
That is still what you want, right?
Yeah, but... can she be
treated in another state,
like... Alaska?
I won't let her anywhere near my family.
She never should have
been in the first place.
You know, when we first
moved into this house,
we didn't have money for a furnace,
and it was winter, so we
bundled you up in sweaters.
You looked like this...
Big ball of yarn,
rolling from room to room.
And we never used the fireplace,
'cause I was scared that
we'd turn our backs
and you'd get burned.
I knew that my one job on
this earth was to make sure
that you didn't get hurt.
And I haven't done a very good job...
Have I?
Still recovering?
From the anniversary dinner.
Yeah. Yeah.
Was he surprised?
Mm-hmm. It was a really big surprise.
Where were you last night?
Were you with Caleb?
No, he's being really weird.
Every time I try to make plans with him,
he says he's busy, but he won't
tell me what he's doing.
Why don't you just ask him? Be honest.
Wow. It's like the world's
fattest man giving dieting tips.
Hello! You're the one who's
sitting on a secret the
size of the "Natterhorn"!
Okay, if you're talking
about Fitz and the kid,
I'm gonna tell him today.
And the goal was never to keep it from him.
I-I'd wake up every morning with
the intention of telling him,
and then I'd go to sleep every night
feeling guilty that I didn't.
At least you have your afternoons free.
Nice bit of support, Hanna.
Oh, and by the way, it's "Matterhorn." Muh.
Aren't you the one that's
supposed to be correcting her?
What?
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Uh, nothing. We didn't really
get much of an anniversary
'cause Toby had to get up
early for work the next day.
That sucks.
Yeah, it does.
Listen, um, I'm gonna skip the brew today
'cause I have a lot of
reading to catch up on,
for English, so I'll
catch you guys at lunch.
Hey, Em.
– Hey.
So, can we see it?
The stuff from his family?
Look, if it's, like,
cards and stuff you wrote to Ali,
you don't have to show us. It's fine.
So, did Spencer tell you about
the key that I dropped?
No, Hanna did.
Said you guys want to
turn it in to the cops...?
So, what do you think?
I think that the mold from my basement
killed some of your brain cells.
Guys, we are not prepared
to tell the cops about A.
I guess you're right.
Mnh. I always hated biology.
Who cares how a cell divides? It just does.
I didn't know that you and
Ali were in bio together.
We weren't.
I lent her my notes to study for the exam.
Then how'd you have the
time to write these?
This is definitely Alison's handwriting.
Yeah, but that's not mine.
Wait. Who's "the beach hottie"?
What?
"You need to tell the
beach hottie tonight."
Then Ali says, "no way, he'll freak out."
What are they talking about?
I want to know who they're talking about.
Turn the page.
That's not Spencer's writing, either.
But I recognise it.
Who does their "G"s like that?
My grandma.
Forget the "G". Look at the "T".
There's someone in here that we do know.
Why is Alison writing about Toby?
If you'll be home I around two P.M.
I've got a free period after lunch
and wanted to stop by so we could talk.
Uh, call me. Love you.
Just go now. Meet him there.
Sooner you do it, the better you'll feel.
Just don't know what else it's gonna take.
You stuck a wet brain in her locker.
She still showed up the next
day with a smile on her face.
Fine. I'll figure it out.
Caleb, I just said I'll do it.
I'll be there around seven.
It's off Route 6. I know it.
Hey. I been looking for you.
Did you get my text?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, you said that you found some of.
Ali's writing in an old notebook?
It's an entire conversation
between Ali and a friend,
but none of us recognise
the friend's handwriting.
Sorry.
I have to get to class.
– You don't get it.
Ali wasn't sharing makeup
tips with this person.
They were talking about a guy that
Ali was secretly involved with.
They call him the beach hottie.
Was Ian ever a lifeguard?
I don't know, but Melissa might. Okay?
Sorry, em, I've really got to get to class.
Spencer...
Ali was scared of this guy,
or at least scared to tell him something.
Okay, well, good luck figuring it out.
What?! Maybe she was just scared
to tell him that she was slutting it up
in three different zip codes in one summer.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that Ali wasn't loyal.
To any of us.
So why do we continue to be loyal to her?
I mean, why should we
care what happens to her?
What happened to her?
Because we do.
Care.
I think that I need to learn to stop.
Wait.
Read.
Alison visited Toby after
he was shipped off to juvie.
What is this?
– You know exactly what it is.
It's time to quit the pen pal routine.
What?
Clearly your time in cellblock four
has done great things for
your literary skills,
but this needs to stop.
I didn't write these.
Listen.
I drove all the way up here
and just got a triple-x
pat down by security.
The least you can do is save me
the trouble of being lied to.
Why are you so convinced that it's me?
Pretty sure Jenna would love
to see your head on a stick.
Jenna would be pretty happy
to see anything, I imagine.
Your step-sis was going through surgery
when some of these were sent.
You wanna know how it turned out?
She's still combing her hair
with an electric toothbrush.
You can go now.
You know, I wasn't the only
one outside that garage.
Why aren't you harassing my friends?
You know what?
I wish I knew who wrote those notes.
I'd offer my services.
You and your posse deserve a lot worse.
I bet you wish you'd kissed
me when you had the chance.
You okay?
Spence, what's wrong?
You're not upset because Ali tried
to hook up with Toby, are you?
Who even knows if she did?
Just because she wrote
it down doesn't mean...
I-I haven't told you guys the truth.
What do you mean? What truth?
That Toby and I broke up
last night.
You did?
What happened?
I'm not really ready to talk about it.
Can we... please just keep it between us?
Yeah.
Thanks.
It's just not that simple.
I mean, she became part of a group.
They influenced her.
I think she just called
him out to punish him.
Well, maybe at first, sure,
but I think she really started
to believe in her own lie.
Spencer.
Are you all right?
– I need to go!
Go where?
– Home.
Is something wrong?
Do you want me to call your mom?
– For what?
You can't just storm out
of the classroom without
a legitimate excuse.
I don't want to be here anymore.
Is that legitimate enough?
What is going on with you?
I don't need to sit in a room
and read books about made-up
people who've been screwed over.
Okay, I get it.
It's not gonna prepare me for
what I have to deal with
when I walk out of this building.
It is a complete waste of my time!
Hey.
Enjoying a nice day in the park?
Oh. Spencer. I didn't even see you, uh...
Been writing down all of
your thoughts and feelings?
Um... actually, I was
working on this, um...
How could you do that to her?
I'm sorry, I-I-I...
No, don't apologise to me.
My God, not after the way
that you've treated her.
Do you even get how much she loves you?
Do you think that it's easy to
find out a secret like that?
Because it's not, okay? It's a burden.
I mean, you're screwed
if you tell and you're
screwed if you don't,
and if you really want to get
pissed and take it out on somebody,
don't dump it on Aria, okay?
No, go after Maggie, because she's actually
the person who had your son
and then kept it a secret for seven years!
What are you talking about?
I thought... I thought, um...
I thought that Aria had told you, and...
Did you not have this conversation?
What... conversation?
What... what are you talking about?
I need to... I need to go.
No, Spencer, wait.
Oh. Thank you.
– No problem.
How's the family?
Mm, everyone's good, you know?
My husband's back in Texas
on base, in training,
and Emily's...
You know, she's okay.
Good.
Hey, can I ask you something?
Emily got a package yesterday
from the family of the kid
who killed Maya St Germain.
Should I be worried that
they have our address?
They shouldn't be contacting you at all.
Sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
No, please. This kind of thing's
much more his territory than mine.
If you want, we can ask that his family
send any future correspondence
directly to us,
let us run interference.
Thanks. I'll think about that.
Hey, you seen Spencer?
Mmm, no, not since this morning.
Everyone said she bailed
on her study group.
She just walked out of class.
Hey.
– Hey.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Could I see you for a moment?
Sure, what's going on. Is everything okay?
Okay?
I don't know. You tell me.
Why was Spencer talking about Maggie?
What?
She said that I had...
That I have a son.
Why would she say that?
Look, can we just talk about this...
We're talking about this right now.
– Ezra, please.
Y-you've been holding onto
this since my birthday?
Ezra...
– So, what, you and my brother...
Just sat there watching
me blow out candles,
and you couldn't find a
way to tell me this?
I was scared.
Of?
– Of what it might do to us.
And then Maggie showed up,
and I thought that she
was going to tell you,
and when she didn't...
Maggie hasn't been a part of
my life since high school.
I see you every day, Aria. You.
You are the person I'm
spending my life with.
You are the person I'm supposed to trust.
You're right.
Thought you needed a little push,
so I pushed "send" for you. – A
You know, the only thing worse than the
break room coffee are the break room bagels.
How's Emily feel about you working here?
How should she feel?
I was hoping it'd make
her feel a little safer.
You know, when I was growing up here,
they could have put up a sign:
"Welcome to Rosewood,
where nothing happens."
But in these past few years...
Detective Wilden, if you're asking
if we're considering moving...
I wouldn't blame you.
There are days when I
wish I could leave too.
But no matter how far I went,
I'd still be taking so
many questions with me.
You know, you may not believe this,
but I know exactly what
Emily's going through.
I'm not following you.
What happened out at that lighthouse,
it's not really something any
young person can process.
Even when it's self-defence.
But uh...
It haunts you. Forever.
I can't really get her
to talk about it much.
Well, I didn't either.
Talk about it.
My second week out of the academy,
I had to defend myself.
The way they taught me.
But that doesn't make watching
someone die any easier.
I was too ashamed to discuss it.
In the law's eyes, I was
clearly in the right.
But having to watch
someone leave this world,
even someone who deserves to be punished...
So when did you finally decide
to start talking about it?
Just now.
Hey.
Tried calling you.
Sorry, I shut my phone off.
Yeah, well, you didn't
come back today to school.
My mom said she might call your parents.
– I figured.
I don't think she wants to. I just think...
Whatever. It's okay. I
won't hold it against her.
Anyway, it's not really why you came.
Well...
No.
I wanted to talk to you...
I know that I shouldn't
have said anything to Fitz.
Okay, I know that.
So, can we please just
skip ahead to the end?
Sorry?
Could we just fast-forward to the part
where you scream or you cry
or just do whatever you need to do, okay?
Wait, I-I didn't come here
to punish you, Spencer.
I know that you were set up.
A sent me a text to rub it in
my face right after Ezra left.
I think that we should stop blaming A
for everything that goes
wrong in our lives,
and start blaming ourselves.
Whoa. Are you actually
defending our enemy right now?
No, I'm just saying that maybe
if we stopped telling lies,
maybe A wouldn't have a reason
to keep on exposing them.
A isn't some tough-love
life coach, Spencer.
We're not being taught to mind
our manners and eat our vegetables.
This person wants to hurt us.
Maybe we deserve it.
Unbelievable.
And thanks for your concern, by the way.
I'm... I'm doing just fine.
Wow. This is crazy.
I totally remember this.
We were stuck in the car
with Ali's parents,
two hours from shore, and
our phones were dead.
It was brutal.
So... who was the "beach hottie"?
Mm, I have no idea.
But you were writing about him.
I just knew him by that name.
Ali never told me who he was.
So you never even met him?
Well, I mean, I probably did.
Honestly, there were so many
hotties down there that summer.
But Ali was being really sketchy about it.
I just assumed he was
seeing her on the side.
He probably had a girlfriend or something.
Would Jason know this person?
If he did, he would have made him sorry
he ever looked at his little sister.
Why?
Will somebody call Jason and
tell him to leave his weed
and come meet up with us.
What are you doing here?
I needed to talk to you.
What's wrong?
I think I'm in trouble.
What do you mean?
I'm late.
Like...?
Yeah.
You mean you weren't using protection?
We were. Just not all the time.
Okay, how late are you?
Two weeks.
Have you ever been late before?
What am I gonna do?
Have you told him?
I can't.
If he finds out, he's gonna kill me.
Ali was...
Listen, I'm not a doctor, Em,
but... she thought that she was.
It's like I said... it was
an intense couple of weeks.
Hey. What are you doing?
Right now? Following Paige.
– What?
She's the one who's been working
with Caleb to bring down Mona.
I'm trying to bust them before A does.
Wait, when did you find this out?
Before lunch.
I was gonna tell you, but Ezra...
Right.
Hanna, be careful.
I-I gotta go. I'll call you later.
Bye.
What is this?
Raspberry flirtini.
Thank you, but I didn't order this.
I know. She ordered it for you.
Hey.
You've been on that couch a while.
How 'bout I make my fancy grilled cheese?
Yeah.
If she were pregnant,
wouldn't that kind of
thing show up on her...
Autopsy?
Not necessarily.
I looked online, and...
If it was really early on,
she was buried over a year ago, so...
What shall we do now?
I don't know.
But look, if some guy in cape
may did get her pregnant
and then threatened to
kill her if he found out,
this is a lot bigger than a key.
This needs to be turned over to the police.
I was worried you were gonna say that.
But I agree.
I'll take you down to the station.
Then I'm coming with you.
No, that's okay. I won't be alone.
My mom will be there.
I'll call you later.
Okay.
I miss you.
And if they play the uncut version of this,
then I'd have to kiss you.
Hey, ladies, shots are a dollar
if you holler in the next half hour,
so step up and get 'em while
they're hot, hot, hot!
Hi. I hope you don't mind. I
just really love this song.
Who is this peroxide piece of trash?
Hey, watch it!
Can I see your ID?
Why would the police want this?
I don't know. Um, Ali wrote in it.
Maybe there's something in there
that could help them figure out
who would want to hurt her.
Okay, let me find out who to give this to.
Hanna?
Hi.
– What are you doing here?
What's that smell? Is that... Tequila?
No. It's actually gin.
A little bit got in my mouth
when, uh, the girl threw
it in my face, so...
Who did? What happened?
Nothing. I just...
I got busted for underage drinking,
which I wasn't even doing.
Unfortunately, "I'm just holding it"
doesn't work on Betty the bouncer.
You were at a club.
More of a bar.
– What bar?
Oh, it was more of a club.
You wouldn't have heard of it.
My mom's gonna kill me.
Hey, Emily. Hanna.
I just spoke with your mom.
She said you wanted to turn something in?
What are you doing? The
cops need to see that.
Unfortunately, he's one of 'em.
I appreciate you bringing this down.
We'll return it to you as soon as we can.
Oh, and Emily,
you did the right thing.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking we could end this.
I'm gonna get a coffee. Do you want one?
No thanks.
I'll take a napkin, for blotting.
What's wrong?
Look who else was in cape may.
I didn't know if you
were really gonna show.
Why wouldn't I?
Said you were 18, right?
So...
How does this work?
Well...
This works...
Whichever way you want it to work.
You called me.
I'm sensing some hesitation here.
What does this go to?
That's what I would like you to find out.
And if you follow him...
He'll lead you there.
Wait.
I'll be in touch.
Hold it.
Can I at least shower first?
My hair is about to crack off my head.
I'm not going to bed
without discussing this.
What were you doing in that bar?
– Mom.
Was it about... exploring a new feeling?
Okay, I wasn't looking for romance.
I was looking for Caleb.
What would Caleb be doing
hanging out in a lesbian bar?
I didn't know it was ladies'
night until I got there.
Look, I was following Paige
because I thought he was
meeting up with her.
For what?
A plan to keep Mona away from my friends.
He and Paige don't want her near us,
so I was just gonna stop them
from doing anything stupid.
And that required ordering a
cocktail and starting a bar fight?
I did not order a cocktail,
and I only danced with
that girl who thought I
was into pink drinks
because I didn't want Paige to see me.
What's a pink drink?
Is that code for something gay?
No, it's just a pink drink.
Can we not do this right now?
Hanna, we're getting to that place again.
What place?
Where I'm sensing you're not
telling me the whole truth.
Well, I'm not hiding
anything from you, okay?
I was just making sure Caleb
didn't get into trouble.
And you got yourself into trouble instead.
Well, that wasn't the plan.
And, honestly, if it keeps
Emily from being messed with,
maybe it was worth it.
What does Emily have to do with this?
Paige might not be a one-girl kind of girl.
She was hooking up with someone
there, and Emily has no clue.
Could I make a suggestion?
Stay out of it.
And use the hot oil treatment on your hair.
Hey.
I was just...
I thought that we were meeting
up at your apartment.
No, we are. Uh...
I was just putting a few things in the car.
Can I just explain to you why...
I don't need you to explain.
I spoke with Maggie, and she told me
that she asked you to keep quiet.
And... she knows it was an
unfair position to put you in.
So are we okay?
Yeah.
Are you okay?
I don't even know how to begin
to answer that question.
Yeah. I understand.
– Good.
Because I don't.
There are, like, a million thoughts
fighting in my head right now, and...
I'm about to meet my son.
But you're leaving?
Yeah, tonight.
– How long?
Uh, I don't know.
Well, where are you staying tonight?
Motel.
I got a college buddy in the area
that I can stay with tomorrow night.
That's good.
Yep.
Can I call you?
Ezra?
We'll talk soon, okay?